

Rittick Chowdhury (Rony)

BANGKOK, 10600, THAILAND · rittick1234@gmail.com · +66 909940304

PROFILE

A curious Data analyst and visualization developer with 9+ years of experience in database development across various line of businesses. Confident in querying in SQL and DAX languages. Seeking a career opportunity to bring detail and precision into data analysis and Business Intelligence.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Lead Data Analyst, Central Retail Digital

Apr 2022 — Present, Bangkok

- Involved in building an enterprise medallion data model(Google BigQuery) that integrated data from multiple sources and enabled consistent data access across the organization.
- Collaborated with DS, DE and Eng Teams to build a data ingestion process to automate the transfer of data from multiple sources into a single database, resulting a reduction of 2 man hour data reconciliation per day for 30+ analysts.
- Analyzed and ideated the design of data models, factor map for business cases and documented data flows to improve system architecture and better data quality.
- Advocated the implementation of best practices on data visualization tools (Microsoft Power BI, Tableau, Looker Studio) to create interactive reports based on our unified data model by following the tool specific best practices which leads to fast performance while concurrent usage. Approximately 80% faster performance.
- Led a team of 5+ people to understand and implement best practices for shaping data in Microsoft Power BI and power platform.

Data Analytics Analyst, ExxonMobil Chemicals (Payroll - Pantheon Corportation)

Aug 2019 — Dec 2021, Bangkok

- Involved in solving the business problem like cross-sale and up-sale opportunity after creating
 the data factor map from historical customer portfolio. Successfully achieved 15% cross sell
 within the same chemical business line.
- Built exploratory dashboard for different social channels like LinkedIn, WeChat, Salesforce
 pardot, Google Analytics, Baidu etc to track different KPIs like email performance(CTR,
 Bounce rate etc.), customer leads(prospects).
- Led a team of 8+ people for creating operational level reports from scratch by following agile and CI/CD approach. i.e. data profiling, data strategy, warehouse design, production deployment of reports.
- Conducted 20+ business problem of operations team and created unified monhtly/weekly
 monitoring dashboard which can track fleets performance and reduce the recurring
 problems.

Analytics Consultant, TATA Consultancy Services

Oct 2018 — Aug 2019, Kolkata

- Proposed, designed and developed a process to up-skill 15 colleagues to help them understand critical business rules.
- Leveraged data analytics to identify areas of improvement and develop actionable plans to address those needs.
- Incorporated analytics tools (Tableau, SSIS, MS Sql Server) to track usage and performance metrics, enabling the team to make data-driven decisions.

DETAILS

NATIONALITY Indian

SKILLS

Data Analysis

Data Visualization

Data Warehousing

Business Intelligence

Data Modeling

SQL

Google BigQuery (GCP)

Data Product Management

Cloud Data Warehousing

Python

Machine Learning

Microsoft Power Platform

Snowflake DWH

Azure SQL

Databricks

Microsoft Synapse Analytics

Power BI

Tableau

Google Data Studio / Looker • Implemented incremental refresh to get more than 50% cost efficiency in table read from the source.

Inventory Analyst, British Telecommunication India

Apr 2017 — Sep 2018, Kolkata

- Collaborated with consumers, analysts, and technical staff to plan, design, develop, test, document, automate, implement, and enhance E2E business analytics capabilities using Tableau Desktop.
- Involved in constructing and maintaining an appropriate, scalable, and easy-to-use
 infrastructure with Tableau online that promotes scalability, sustainability, and that leverages
 recommended best practices.
- Established an inventory control system that improved inventory accuracy by 40%.

Data Analyst, Tech Mahindra Pvt Ltd

Jan 2014 — Apr 2017, Kolkata

- Developed an ETL pipeline to streamline data ingestion and processing for analysis, resulting in a 23% reduction in processing time.
- Designed and optimized SQL queries to improve data retrieval performance.

EDUCATION

West Bengal University of Technology, B.Tech (Computer Science)

Jun 2008 — Jul 2012, Kolkata

COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

DA-100: Analyzing Data with Microsoft Power BI, Microsoft

Jul 2021 — Jul 2024

Tableau Desktop Certified Associate, Tableau Software

Apr 2021 — Apr 2023